Inventory of the Klaus Kirchner collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Soviet Central Series, 1941-1945; 1-5 (Box 1-5:)
  - Eine neue Gemeinheit Hitlers…, 1943 July (Folder 4: 2613)
    15x22 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [A new nastiness of Hitler. To all officers and soldiers of the German Wehrmacht! Comrades! Our division laid down our arms in the pocket of Stalingrad... Hitler's new nastiness is to declare we all had died in Stalingrad… He needs this lie of our death for his propaganda... Do a good turn and tell our relatives we are alive... He who goes with Hitler will perish at the front. He who breaks with Hitler and comes to the Russians will be far from the front in complete safety...]. Names and addresses of former members of the 44th Infantry Division are given, officers are mentioned on top of the list.
  - Gebt Euch freiwillig gefangen! Deutsche Soldaten! In letzter Zeit geben sich..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2618)
    14x20 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [Go to captivity on your free will!... In recent times more and more German soldiers went into captivity of the Red Army...]
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor? Nr. 206, 1943 July (Folder 4: 2620)
    16x20 cm - 2 - preservation: 1 - 7.1943 - description: [What is happening in Germany? No. 206... German soldiers! Read, what the SS-men do in the German hinterland... The SS is in the hinterland, soldiers die at the front ... Himmler is favoring sexual excesses... SS is plundering the property of bombed out families... SS is making fun of soldier's wives...]
  - Die deutsche Offensive in Raum von Kursk und die Gauner aus dem..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2621)
    14x20 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [The German offensive in the Kursk area and the swindler from Hitler's headquarters... The offensive of the Germans which started in July 5th has had no success so far...]
  - Illustriertes Blatt Nr. 11, 1943 July (Folder 4: 2622)
    16x22 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [Illustrated Paper German POWs in Soviet Russia No. 11... This is the way they looked when they surrendered at Stalingrad. This is the way they look now in Russian captivity...]. Six photographs: German POWs on their way from capitulation to the safety of their camp and their activity to influence their comrades still fighting for Hitler.
  - DAS NEUE ABENTEUER HITLERS ZUM SCHEITERN VERURTEILT..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2625)
    10x14 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [Hitler's new adventure will fail... On July 5th Hitler started his new offensive near Kursk with 15 tanks, one mechanized, and 14 infantry divisions... losses are unbelievable and the result is zero...]
  - ACHTUNG! Ein neuer Betrug! DEUTSCHE SOLDATEN! Tag für Tag…, 1943 July (Folder 4: 2626)
    10x13 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [Attention! A new fraud!... Day for day they tried to tell you in the last months: "Time is working for us!" That was a lie and a fraud!...]. Note: On July 5th Hitler started his new offensive near Kursk.
  - Illustriertes Blatt Nr. 12, 1943 July (Folder 4: 2629)
    16x22 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description of [Illustrated Paper No. 12. German POWs in Soviet Russia.] Six Photographs: Note: POWs eating on tables covered with white linen and being served by a young Russian girl.
  - Erklärung eines deutschen Oberleutnants, der auf die Seite der Sowjettruppen, 1943 July (Folder 4: 2637)
    20x27 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: First Lieutenant Hans Frankenfeld gives a curriculum vitae and his observations in Russian captivity. Portrait photograph.
  - Vor Kursk haben die Illusionen der deutschen Soldaten ihr Grab gefunden…, 1943 July (Folder 4: 2638)
    11x17 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [In front of Kursk the illusions of German soldiers have found their grave... The break down of the German summer offensive - is the decisive defeat of the German army...]. Note: On July 5th Hitler started his new offensive near Kursk.
  - Warum ist die neue Offensive Hiders zusammengebrochen? Am 5. Juli 1943..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2642)
    14x20 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [Why broke the new offensive Hitler's down?!... Because the time for Hitler's successes is over.]
  - Zwei Sommeroffensiven Am 5. Juli begann Hitler die General offensive auf..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2644)
    20x17 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [Two summer offensives. On 5th July Hitler began his general offensive in Kursk. In 10 days the Germans lost 1,392 airplanes, 2,818 tanks (more than 700 "Tiger"), and about 100,000 soldiers and officers dead. Without the slightest success Hitler was pushed to the defensive... On 12th July began the Russian offensive in the Orel area...]. Two photographs.
  - Die Geschichte wiederholt sich Juli 1943 - Juli 1918 DEUTSCHE..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2645)
    14x20 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [History is repeating itself… July 1943 - July 1918... Exactly 25 years ago, in July 1918, Kaiser Wilhelm tried also to start a last desperate offensive...]
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 231, 1943 July (Folder 4: 2646)
    17x22 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 231... The price of the new Hitler adventure... A cemetery of "Tiger" tanks...]
  - Aus ist's mit dem Sommer für die deutsche Armee! Offiziere und Soldaten!..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2648)
    11x16 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [The summer for the German army is over... Instead of summer new defeats have arrived. What will come are autumn and winter and the unavoidable catastrophe of the German army...]
  - Achtung! Wichtig für jeden Soldaten an der Ostfront..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2649)
    11x16 cm - 2 - paper: red - preservation: 1. Description: [Attention! Important for every soldier at the Eastern front!... To prove, you have lost this war already is self-evident. After Stalingrad and Tunis...].
  - Wenn deutsche Soldaten und Offiziere sich ergeben..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2650)
    14x10 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: ["If German soldiers and officers capitulate the Red Army makes them prisoners and saves their lives."... Stalin...]. Safe conduct with special conditions promised for those capitulating on their free will. The leaflet is propagating desertion.
  - Angriff oder Verteidigung? Deutsche Offiziere und..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2651)
    19x18 cm - 2 - paper: blue - preservation: 1. Description: [Attack or defence?... In Kursk Hitler had tried to attack. Near Orel the Germans were in the defence...]. Two photographs, one photomontage.
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 232, 1943 July (Folder 4: 2653)
    21x16 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 232... The Soviet troops are advancing... Where German "Tigers" did not get through Russian tanks did... German soldiers surrender with their lorries... Russian artillery is destroying "Tigers"...] Photomontage: Destroyed German tanks.
  - Befehl des Obersten Befehlshabers an General der Armee Genossen..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2658)
    14x20 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: Stalin is promoting some of his generals.
  - Er ist der Schuldige! Sterben muss er! Sonst gibt es bald kein Deutschland..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2665)
    22x15 cm - 2 - blue - preservation: 1. Description: [He is the guilty one! He must die! Otherwise Germany will soon cease to exist... Soldier, your child is calling you... Soldier follow the call of your child: Save yourself for your child, for your family. ..]. Photomontage.
  - Österreicher! Soldaten der..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2666)
    13x21 cm - 2 - red - preservation: 1. Description: [Austrians! Soldiers of the 2nd, 8th, 12th tank division and the 262th Infantry Division!... The war is coming closer to Austria... Austrians are in the majority on this sector of the front, an armed majority in Hitler's army... After the war you will return to your home in an Austria which will no longer be subjected by Hitler...]
  - Italiens erster Sieg. Mussolini. DEUTSCHER SOLDAT!..., 1943 July (Folder 4: 2676)
    13x17 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [Italy's first victory. Mussolini (his name is crossed out). German soldier! Read again the latest news...]. Caricature.
  - Befehl des Obersten Befehlshabers der Roten Armee an Generaloberst..., 1943 August (Folder 4: 2684)
    14x20 cm - 2 - preservation: 1 - 8.1943 - description: Stalin is promoting some of his generals.
  - Liquidierung des Order Aufmarschgebietes der Deutschen und Einnahme..., 1943 August (Folder 4: 2690)
    13x19 cm - 4 - preservation: 1. Description: [Liquidation of the German attack and occupation of Orel and Belgorod...]
  - Gib Dich freiwillig gefangen!..., 1943 August (Folder 4: 2696)
    11x14 cm - 2 - brown - preservation: 1. Description: [Did you read the booklet of the "840"? ..]. NOTE: Under the headline "Surrender voluntarily!" ("Gib Dich freiwillig gefangen!") the Soviet Government produced and disseminated series of miniature different illustrated leaflets. The following codes were used: 2696, 2698 to 2704, 2706, 2857 to 2860, 2886 to 2893.
  - Wohin? Mit Hitler Ohne Hitler. WÄHLE! Mit Hitler - das ist der alte Weg..., 1943 August (Folder 4: 2711)
    15x10cm - 2 - paper: blue - preservation: 1. Description: [Where to? With Hitler or without Hitler...]
  - Warum weinst du, Mutti? Warum ich weine? Mein armes Kind..., 1943 August (Folder 4: 2712)
    16x11 cm - 2 - paper: blue - preservation: 1. Description: [Why do you cry, Mama? ..]. Photomontage, see also leaflet code 2380, poem by Erich Weinert.
  - ERICH WEINERT DENK AN DEIN KIND! Wohl diese Nacht..., 1943 August (Folder 4: 2713)
    11x15cm - 2 - paper: blue - preservation: 1. Description: poem on reverse [Think about your child! It is dreaming of you! Your child is asking for you: Mother, is father not yet here?...]. Photomontage and poem by Erich Weinert.
  - Willst nach Hause du gelangen..., 1943 August (Folder 4: 2714)
    11x15cm - 2 - paper: blue - preservation: 1. Description: If you want to come home, Turn to Russian captivity. [Encouragement: Listen, soldier. Remember well! If you want to see again child and wife, don't be discouraged!]. Drawing and poem by Erich Weinert.
  - LETZTE WARNUNG! Geht zurück..., 1943 August (Folder 4: 2715)
    12x15cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [Last warning! Retreat, before it is too late!... Remember well, what we tell you: the longer you stay on our land the more will your guilt grow... The soldiers of the Red Army]
  - Was bedeutet die Evakuierung von Berlin..., 1943 August (Folder 4: 2716)
    14x19cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [What does the evacuation of Berlin and Hamburg mean?... Do away with Hitler - he is guilty of this war, he has condemned your families to death and the war will be over!]
  - Wer drückt sich rum in der Etappe..., 1943 August (Folder 4: 2718)
    15x11 cm - 2 - paper: blue - preservation: 1. Description: [Who is hiding in the hinterland.. Who is amusing himself with the fiance of the soldier...SS. The sooner the better! German soldiers! While you risk here your life, at your home your family is breaking apart. The SS and their fellow rogues approach your brides and wives... Don't wait until your luck is broken. Save, what can be saved. Leave the front...] Photomontage.
  - Als er Abschied nahm... Als er wiederkam..., 1943 August (Folder 4: 2721)
    11x15cm - 2 - paper: blue - preservation: 1. Description: [When he took leave... When he returned... This song was found in the possession of a German soldier who had died at the Eastern front...]. Photomontage and song.
  - KRIEGSKALENDER 1943 AUGUST 8. August 1918. DER SCHWARZE TAG der... (Folder 4: 2726)
    14x17cm 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [War calendar 1943 August 8th... Ludendorff: "August 8, 1918, was the decline of the ability to fight... To fight the war took the character of playing hazard... The war had to be ended..."]. The code 2627 is printed erroneously on this leaflet.
  - Verluste der faschistischen deutschen Truppen an der sowjetisch-deutschen..., 1943 August (Folder 5: 2727)
    10x15cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [Losses of the fascist German troops on the Soviet German front from 5th July to 20th August 1943...]
  - KRIEGSKALENDER 1943 AUGUST. Vor 185 Jahren, am 25. August... (Folder 5: 2737)
    14x17 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [War calendar 1943. August 185 years ago, on 25th August 1758... Frederick the Great: "An army which should try to invade Russia further than Smolensk is doomed."]
  - Nach CHARKOW... 1943 AUGUST 30 MONTAG Operationsbericht vom... (Folder 5: 2739)
    14x18cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [After Kharkov. 1943 August. Report on operations of the Red Army on 30th August...]
  - KEINE ILLUSIONEN... DEUTSCHE SOLDATEN! Nach Stalingrad..., 1943 September (Folder 5: 2740)
    14x17cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [No illusions... After Stalingrad they tried to console you... It was evident the Germans can no longer attack in summer... They are not even able to defend themselves...]
  - Das "siegreiche" Viergespann am Scheidewege. Deutsche Offiziere und..., 1943 September (Folder 5: 2742)
    15x11 cm - 2 - preservation: 1 - paper: yellow - description: [The "victorious" four-horse carriage at the decision... German officers and soldiers! This is the way the Hitler block is presenting itself. Only a blind man does not see that Hitler's case is lost... Put down your weapons! Go into captivity voluntarily...]. Drawing similar to leaflet code 3196, only one "horse" i.e. Hungary, has remained.
  - "Der Sturz Mussolinis ist eine innere Angelegenheit Italiens"..., 1943 September (Folder 5: 2743)
    11x16cm - 2 - yellow - preservation: 1. Description: ["The toppling of Mussolini is an internal affair of Italy" or: Mussolini's today is Hitler's tomorrow. German officers and soldiers! After the Italian people had ousted Mussolini Hitler's propaganda did not have much to say... Put down your arms! Go to captivity voluntarily...]
  - "Ruhe und Ordnung herrschen in Deutschland"..., 1943 September (Folder 5: 2744)
    11x15cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description: ["Quiet and order rule in Germany" or HIMMLER is appointed interior minister. Hitler has sent you to Russia to perish. Your families have been turned over to Himmler the henchman...]
  - Hinter der Kulisse..., 1943 September (Folder 5: 2745)
    12x15cm - 2 - yellow - preservation: 1. Description: [Behind the scene...]. The leaflet is reporting on a diplomatic note of the Allies to neutral countries warning them not to grant asylum to Nazi politicians. [German officers and soldiers! Hitler is completely bankrupt. Now he and his helpers are looking for a hideout in neutral countries...]
  - KRIEGSKALENDER 1943 SEPTEMBER 1943. Vor vier Jahren, am... (Folder 5: 2747)
    14x17cm - 2 - preservation: 1
  - Aus dem Befehl des Obersten Befehlshabers der Roten Armee vom 8..., 1943 September (Folder 5: 2751)
    11x15 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: A Stalin order and a report of German losses.
  - KRIEGSKALENDER 1943 SEPTEMBER 5-7 September 1812... (Folder 5: 2752)
    14x17 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [War calendar 1943 September. 5th to 7th September 1812. Battle at Borodino, victory of the Russians and destruction of Napoleon's army... Napoleon: "It is possible to invade Russia but you cannot get out of it."]
  - DEUTSCHE SOLDATEN! LASST EUCH RATEN: RUFT DEN RUSSEN..., 1943 October (Folder 5: 2774)
    23x16 cm - 2 - paper: red - preservation: 1. Description: [German soldiers! Take our advice: Call out to the Russians: "SDAIUS, TOVARISCHI, NE STRELAITE".]. Photomontage, see leaflet code 1850. Reverse: [Have a look at the map!...]
  - Vom 19. bis zum 30. Oktober 1943 tagte DEKLARATION über die Verantwortlichkelt..., 1943 October (Folder 5: 2793)
    14x20 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [From 19th to 30th October 1943 a conference took place in Moscow... Declaration about the responsibility of the Hitler-Fascists for committed bestialities... Churchill, Roosevelt, Stalin.]
  - ERGEBNISSE des Sommerfeldzugs der..., 1943 November (Folder 5: 2794)
    14x20cm - 4 - preservation: 1. Description: [Results of the summer campaign of the Red Army... losses of the enemy during the summer campaign more than 2,700,000 dead, wounded and POWs...]
  - Vom 19. bis zum 30. Oktober 1943 ... DEKLARATION über Italien..., 1943 November (Folder 5: 2795)
    14x20cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [From 19th to 30th October 1943 a conference took place in Moscow... Declaration about Italy...]
  - Englisch-sowjetisch-amerikanisches Kommunique über die Konferenz..., 1943 November (Folder 5: 2796)
    14x20cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description: [English-Soviet-American communique on the conference of the three ministers in Moscow. From 19th to 30th October 1943 a conference took place in Moscow... The Ministers declare the independence of Austria.]
  - Vom 19. bis zum 30. Oktober 1943... DEKLARATION über die Verantwortlichkeit..., 1943 November (Folder 5: 2804)
    16x23 cm - 2 - paper: blue, red - preservation: 1. See part description: [From 19th to 30th October 1943 a conference took place in Moscow... Declaration about the responsibility of the Hitler-Fascists... Churchill, Roosevelt, Stalin.]
  - VIER GEBOTE, um der Vergeltung zu entgehen..., 1943 November (Folder 5: 2809)
    16x21 cm - 2 - paper: red - preservation: 1. Description: [Four commandments to avoid retaliation... We want to send you this warning: Everybody, taking part in crimes committed by Hitler-Fascists will be dealt with severely... He who wants to avoid retaliation should heed the following four commandments: 1. Do not commit murder! 2...]. Illustration of four commandments.
  - Und wo steht Euer nächster "Ostwall"?..., 1943 November (Folder 5: 2815)
    17x20 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [And where is your next "East Wall"? ..]. Hitler is promising since 1942 a wall in the East but German troops have been retreating ever since. Hitler caricature: "East Wall."
  - STALIN SPRICHT Die Hitlerarmee ist nicht mehr..., 1943 November (Folder 5: 2820)
    17x20 cm - 2 - paper: red, paper: rose - preservation: 1 - 11.1943 - description: [Stalin is speaking. Hitler's army is not what it was...]
  - STALIN SPRICHT Hitlerdeutschland vor der..., 1943 November (Folder 5: 2821)
    17x20 cm - 2 - paper: red, paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [Stalin is speaking. Hitler Germany is facing a catastrophe...]
  - STALIN SPRICHT Festigung der Antihitlerkoalition..., 1943 November (Folder 5: 2823)
    14x24 cm - 2 - paper: red, paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [Stalin is speaking. Consolidation of the anti-Hitler coalition. Disintegration of the fascist block...]
  - Die Russen über den Dnjeper!..., 1943 November (Folder 5: 2827)
    14x21 cm - 2 - paper: red - preservation: 1. Description: [The Russians are crossing the Dnieper river...]. Map: Russian gains until November 1943.
  - "Zu Befehl!"..., 1943 November (Folder 5: 2828)
    19x21cm - 2 - brown - preservation: 1. Description: ["Yes. Sir!"... Blind obedience is the duty of a soldier...]. Photomontage.
  - Worauf rechnet Ihr noch? Soldaten!..., 1943 December (Folder 5: 2833)
    16x22cm - 2 - blue - preservation: 1. Description: [What are you counting on? .. Are you counting on a compromise peace? .. Are you counting on wonder weapons... Even on your retreat a Russian bullet is waiting for each of you...]. Photomontage.
  - Konferenz der Leiter in Teheran...DEKLARATION DER DREI MÄCHTE..., 1943 December (Folder 5: 2835)
    18x23cm - 2 - blue, red - preservation: 1. Description: [Conference of the leaders of the three united powers... Declaration of the three powers... Roosevelt, Stalin, Churchill]. Flags of the three powers.
  - Vom 19. bis zum 30. Oktober 1943... DEKLARATION über die Verantwortlichkeit…, 1943 December (Folder 5: 2842)
    16x23cm - 2 - blue, red - preservation: 1. Description: [From 19th to 30th October 1943 a conference took place in Moscow... Declaration about the responsibility of the Hitler-Fascists... Churchill, Roosevelt, Stalin.]
  - Gib Dich freiwillig gefangen!..., 1943 December (Folder 5: 2857)
    11x14 cm - 2 - brown - preservation: 1. Description: life of German POWs. NOTE: Under the headline "Surrender voluntarily!" ("Gib Dich freiwillig gefangen!") the Soviet Government produced and disseminated series of miniature and different illustrated leaflets. The following codes were used: 2696, 2698 to 2704, 2706, 2857 to 2860, 2886 to 2893.
  - Erzwungene Eingeständnisse des Generals Dittmar SOLDATEN!..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2873)
    14x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: a German military commentator is describing the situation at the fronts in his speech on the New year 1944.
  - DER KRIEG IST ZU HITLERS PRIVATSACHE GEWORDEN..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2875)
    10x22 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [The war turned to be Hitler's private affair. Soldiers, speak up, do you want to perish for that?...]
  - Wer wird zermürbt und wer zermürbt?..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2881)
    14x22 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [Who is being worn down and who is doing this?... The end of the war has already been decided...]
  - "Durchhalten!" WOZU? Deutsche Soldaten..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2882)
    14x20 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: ["Hold out!" What for? ... Since Stalingrad you hear the same "Hold out!"...In the end "holding out" led to bloodletting of German troops...]
  - Gebt Euch freiwillig gefangen, ehe es zu spät ist! DEUTSCHE SOLDATEN!..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2884)
    10x14 cm - 4 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [Go into captivity before it is too late!...]. The leaflet provides a sample identification card promising special treatment for those POWs who surrendered voluntarily, i.e. to desert.
  - Gebt Euch freiwillig gefangen, ehe es zu spät ist! DEUTSCHE SOLDATEN!..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2885)
    17x25 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [Map of the Russian offensive. The German High Command (OKW) maintains the Wehrmacht shortens the front line by retreating. But the map shows the frontline is 700 km longer than before...]. Note: the red front-line is drawn in the silhouette of several Russian tanks, model T-34.
  - Gib Dich freiwillig gefangen!..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2886)
    15x11 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description: [This is going to be a snowman...]. Three photographs of German POWs.
  - Gib Dich freiwillig gefangen!..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2887)
    11x15 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description: [A Christmas tree is being decorated...]. Two photographs of German POWs.
  - Gib Dich freiwillig gefangen!..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2888)
    11x15 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description: [''Winter-battle''] with snowballs. Three photographs of German POWs.
  - Gib Dich freiwillig gefangen!..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2889)
    11x15 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description: Christmas tree in a camp. Two photographs of German POWs.
  - Gib Dich freiwillig gefangen!..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2890)
    11x15 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description: Writing letters home. Three photographs of German POWs.
  - Gib Dich freiwillig gefangen!..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2891)
    11x15 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description: [We celebrate Christmas]. Three photographs of German POWs.
  - Gib Dich freiwillig gefangen!..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2892)
    15x11 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description: Celebrating Christmas. Two photographs of German POWs.
  - Gib Dich freiwillig gefangen!..., 1944 January (Folder 5: 2893)